好的，今天的话题是分布式交易，这些交易确实是为了
all right today's topic is distributed
transactions and these come in really to
实施部分，这就是我将介绍它们的第一部分
implementation pieces and that's how
I'll cover them the first big piece of
并发控制第二个是原子提交，也是分布式的原因
concurrency control the second is atomic
commit and the reason why distributive
交易的出现是，这对于有大量交易的人来说非常常见
transactions come up is that it's very
frequent for people with large amounts
数据最终在许多不同的服务器上拆分或分片数据，因此
of data to end up splitting or sharding
the data over many different servers so
也许如果您经营一家银行，例如，您一半的银行余额
maybe if you're running a bank for
example the bank balances for half your
客户是一台服务器，另一半是银行余额
customers are one server and the bank
balances for the other half are on a
不同的服务器让我们做到这一点，例如将负载分为处理负载和
different server let's do it like split
the load both the processing load and
还有其他方面的空间需求，也许您正在录制
the space requirements this comes up for
other things too maybe you're recording
您知道某个网站上的文章的票数很重要
vote counts on articles at a website you
know the maybe there's so many millions
数百万票数的一半是，并且在一台服务器上，
millions of articles half the vote
counts are and are on one server and
一半或一半以上的癌症，但有些手术需要触摸修改或
half the vote cancer or another but some
operations require touching modifying or
在多个不同的服务器上读取数据，所以如果我们在做银行
reading data on multiple different
servers so if we're doing a bank
从一个客户转移到另一口井，他们的余额可能不同
transfer from one customer into another
well their balances may be on different
服务器，因此为了达到平衡，我们必须修改数据读取和
servers and therefore in order to do the
balance we have to modify data read and
在两台不同的服务器上写入数据，我们真的很想以一种方式构建
write data on two different servers and
we'd really like to or one way building
这些系统，我们将在稍后的课程中以其他方式构建其他系统
these systems and we'll see others later
on in the course one way to build the
系统只是试图隐藏将数据拆分为多个数据的复杂性
system just try to hide the complexity
of splitting this data across multiple
服务器尝试向应用程序程序员隐藏它，这就像
servers try to hide it from the
application programmer and this is like
数十年来，传统上一直是数据库问题，因此
traditionally has been a database
concern for for many decades and so a
当今的许多材料都起源于数据库，但是这些思想已被使用
lot of today's material originated with
databases but the ideas have been used
在分布式系统中更为广泛，您不必将其称为
much more widely in distributed systems
which you wouldn't necessarily call a
人们通常打包并发的传统数据库
traditional database the way people sort
of usually package up concurrency
控制加
control plus
原子提交在抽象上称为交易，我们之前已经看到过
atomic commit is in abstraction called a
transaction which we've seen before and
这个想法是，您认识的程序员有很多不同的操作可能
the idea is that the programmer you know
has a bunch of different operations may
在数据库中的不同记录上，他们希望所有这些操作
be on different records in the database
they'd like all those operations to be
单个单元的排序，不会因故障或其他观察而拆分
sort of a single unit and not split by
failures or by observation from other
活动和交易处理系统将需要
activities and the transaction
processing system will require the
程序员标记阅读顺序的开始和结束，
programmer to mark the beginning and the
end of that sequence of reading and
编写和更新操作，以标记开始和结束
writing and updating operations in order
to mark the beginning and of the
交易和交易处理系统肯定会
transaction and the transaction
processing system has certainly will
提供有关开始和结束之间发生的某些保证
provide certain guarantees about what
happens between the beginning and the
结束，例如，假设我们正在运行
end
so for example supposing we're running
我们的银行，并且我们希望从用户X的帐户转帐到的帐户
our bank and we want to do a transfer
from account of user X to the account of
现在，整个用户的余额都从10开始，因此最初
user wide now these balances from both
of them start out as 10 so initially
暴露10 y等于10和x和y我的意思是成为数据库中的记录，我们
expose 10 y equals 10 and x and y I'm
mean to be records in a database and we
要转移，我们实际上会想象有两笔交易
want to transfer we will actually
imagine that there's two transactions
可能同时运行一个从帐户X转移美元的操作
that might be running at the same time
one to transfer a dollar from account X
到帐户Y和另一笔交易对所有帐户进行审计
to account Y and the other transaction
to do an audit of of all the accounts at
银行确保银行中的总金额永远不会
the bank to make sure that the total
amount of money in the bank never
会发生变化，因为毕竟，如果您进行转账，您应该知道总数不应
changes because after all if you do
transfers you know the total shouldn't
即使您在多个帐户之间转移资金也可以更改
change even if you move money between
accounts in order to express this with
交易我们可能有两个交易，第一个交易呼叫
transactions we might have two
transactions the first transaction call
t1是程序员应该标记的传输标记。
it t1 is the transfer well mark the
programmer is expected to mark the
以begin交易开始
beginning of it with the begin
transaction which all right at the
开始，然后对两个记录中两个记录的两个余额进行操作
beginning and then the operations on the
two balances on the two records in the
数据库，所以我们可以添加[音乐]
database so we might add
[Music]
一个可能将余额X加一个，然后将Y加-1，然后我们需要标记结尾
one might add one the balance X and add
-1 to Y and then we need to mark the end
根据交易当前，我们可能有一笔要检查的交易
by the transaction currently we might
have a transaction that's going to check
所有余额对所有余额进行审计，以查找总金额或查看所有余额
all the balance do an audit of all the
balances find the sum or look at all the
余额确保它们加起来即使不改变也不会改变
balances make sure they add up to the
number that doesn't change despite
转账，所以我在考虑审计交易的第二笔交易
transfers so the second transaction I'm
thinking about the audit transaction
我们还需要标记起点和终点，这一次我们只是在阅读
also we need to mark the beginning and
end this time we're just reading there's
只读交易，我们需要获取所有帐户的当前余额
a read-only transaction we need to get
the current balances of all the accounts
列出他们现在只是这两个帐户，所以我们有两个临时帐户
lists they were just these two accounts
for now so we have two temporary
我们将要读取的第一个变量将是余额X的值
variables we're gonna read the first one
it's going to be the value of balance X
恰到好处意味着我们正在读取该记录，我们也读取Y，然后打印
just right get to mean we're reading
that record we also read Y and we print
他们俩，这是交易的结束，问题是什么是
them both and that's the end of the
transaction the question is what are
这两项交易的法律结果是我们要做的第一件事
legal results from these two
transactions that's the first thing we
要确定的是给定的起始状态就是两个
want to establish is what are you know
given the starting state namely the two
十美元的余额以及您跑步后的最终结果是什么
balances for ten dollars and what could
be the final results after you've run
这些交易可能同时进行，所以我们需要一个概念
both these transactions maybe at the
same time so we need a notion of what
是正确的，一旦我们知道我们需要能够制造机械
would be correct and once we know that
we need to be able to build machinery
实际上将能够执行这些事务并仅获得那些
that will actually be able to execute
these transactions and get only those
尽管存在并发和失败，但仍能给出正确答案，所以首先是正确性
correct answers despite concurrency and
failures so first what's correctness
良好的数据库通常具有正确性的概念，称为酸
well databases usually have a notion of
correctness called acid
或bb-8是酸，它代表原子，这意味着
or bb-8 is acid and it stands for atomic
and this means that a transaction that
有多个步骤，您可能会写多个不同的步骤
has multiple steps
you know maybe writes multiple different
记录尽管有故障但还是有故障，应该所有权利
records if there's a failure despite
failures either all of the right should
完成或全部都不做，不应该因为尴尬而失败
be done or none of them it shouldn't be
the case that a failure at an awkward
事务中间的时间应该使更新完成的一半
time in the middle of a transaction
should leave half the updates completed
看不见，一半的更新从未完成，要么全部要么一无所有，所以这是或
invisible and half the updates never
done it's all or nothing so this is or
尽管有失败，但C代表一致，实际上我们并没有
not despite failures the C stands for
consistent it's actually we're not going
担心这一点通常是指数据库将
to worry about that that's usually meant
to refer to the fact that database will
强制应用程序声明的某些不变式，这不是我们真正的
enforce certain invariants declared by
the application it's not really our
尽管今天很重要，但通常代表孤立
concern today the I though it's quite
important it usually stands for isolated
这实际上是两个事务是否在运行的属性
and this is a really a property of
whether or not two transactions that run
同时可以在交易发生之前看到彼此的变化
at the same time can see each other's
changes before the transactions have
完成了他们是否可以看到某种中间更新以及
finished whether or not they can see
sort of intermediate updates and from
在另一笔交易的中间，您的目标是不，而
the middle of another transaction and
your goal is no and the sort of
大多数人通常所说的隔离技术特有的东西是
technical specific thing that most
people generally mean by isolation is
事务执行是可序列化的，我将说明
that the transaction execution is
serializable and I'll explain what that
意味着有点，但是归结为交易看不到对方的
means in a bit but it boils down to
transactions can't see each other's
更改看不到中间状态，而只能看到完整的交易结果
changes can't see intermediate states
but only complete transaction results
最后的D代表耐用
and the final D stands for durable
这意味着交易在客户或其他任何对象之后提交
and this means that after a transaction
commits after the client or whatever
提交交易的程序会从数据库获得回复
program that submitted the transaction
gets a reply back from the database
说是的，您知道我们已经执行了您的交易
saying yes
you know we've executed your transaction
酸中的D表示交易会修改数据库
the D in acid means that the
transactions modifications the database
会很持久，因为它们仍会存在，不会被某些物体擦除
will be durable that they'll still be
there they won't be erased by a some
某种故障，实际上这意味着必须将内容写入
sort of failure and in practice that
means that stuff has to be written into
一些非易失性存储持久性存储（例如磁盘），所以今天您是
some non-volatile storage persistent
storage like a disk and so today you are
实际上，在整个课程中，我们的关注点都将围绕着
in fact for this whole course really our
concerns are going to revolve around
关于失败的良好行为良好的尊重
good behavior with respect to failure
good respect good behavior with respect
多个并行活动中的其他活动，并确保数据
to other from multiple parallel
activities and making sure that the data
即使有东西崩溃，他们仍然在那里吗？
is there still they are after even if
something crashes so the most
对我们来说，有趣的部分是孤立冰的具体定义
interesting part of this for us is the
specific definition of ice of isolated
或可序列化，所以在讨论它之前，我将对其进行布局
or serializable so I'm going to lay that
out before before talking about how it
实际上适用于这些交易，因此通常将孤立的ioan和
actually applies to these transactions
so the ioan isolated is usually and the
如果执行一组交易，则对此的定义
definition for this if a set of
transactions executes you know
同时或多或少同时是您的结果集和
concurrently more or less at the same
time they you are the set of results and
这里的结果指的是由任何人创建的新数据库记录
here the results refer to both the new
database records created by any
修改交易可能执行的操作，以及
modifications the transactions might do
and in addition any output that the
产生了如此广泛的交易，因为这两个交易增加了
transaction is produced so broader
transactions these two adds since they
变更记录他们的需求变更记录是结果的一部分，并且
change records their needs change
records are part of the results and the
此print语句的输出是结果的一部分，因此
output of this print statement is part
of the results so the definition of
可序列化表示结果可序列化
serializable says the results are
serializable
如果存在一些执行交易的顺序，那么我们要说
if there exists some order of execution
of the transactions so we're gonna say a
事务的特定执行并行并发执行是
specific execution parallel concurrent
execution of transactions is
可序列化，如果存在某个序列顺序，则在此实际上强调了序列
serializable if there exists some serial
order really emphasizing serial here a
产生相同结果的相同事务的执行顺序
serial order of execution of those same
transactions that yields the same result
因为实际执行与此处的差异是实际
as the actual execution and the
difference of here is the actual
执行中可能有很多并行性，但这是必需的
execution may have had a lot of
parallelism in it but it's required to
一次产生与某个结果相同的结果
produce the same result as some one at a
time
执行相同的交易，因此您检查是否
execution of the same transactions and
so the way you check whether an
执行是否可序列化是一些并发执行是否可序列化
execution is serializable whether some
concurrent execution is serializable is
您查看结果，看看是否一次可以找到一个
you look at the results and see if you
can find actually some one at a time
执行确实产生相同结果的相同交易，因此对于我们
execution of the same transactions that
does produce the same results so for our
交易在这里，只有两个订单，一次只有两个
transaction up here there's only two
orders there's only two one at a time
串行订单可用事务1然后​​事务2或事务2然后
serial orders available transaction 1
then transaction 2 or transaction 2 then
交易1，所以我们只看一下它们将产生的结果
transaction 1 and so we can just look at
the results that they would produce if
在这些命令中的每个命令中一次执行一个，所以如果我们先执行t1然后执行t2
executed one at a time in each of these
orders so if we execute t1 and then t2
那么我们得到x等于11
then we get x equals 11
为什么等于9和此打印语句，因为t1首先执行了此打印
why equals 9 and this print statement
since t1 executed first this print
语句看到这两个更新的值，因此它将打印字符串11 9
statement sees these two updated values
and so it will print the string 11 9 the
其他可能的顺序是，也许先运行t2，然后再运行t1，在这种情况下
other possible order is that perhaps t2
ran first and then t1 and in that case
t2在修改之前会看到2条记录，但是修改后
t2 will see that 2 records before they
were modified but the modifications will
由于t1稍后运行，因此仍会发生，因此最终结果将再次为x等于
still take place since t1 runs later so
the final results will again be x equals
11 y等于9，但是这次t2在我们的值之前浸透了，所以这是两个
11 y equal 9 but this time t2 sodded
before our values so these are the two
可序列化的合法结果，以及如果我们发现运行中还有其他问题
legal results for serializability and if
we ever see anything else from running
这两个事务同时我们将知道数据库是
these two transactions at the same time
we'll know that the database were
运行不提供正在执行的可序列化执行
running against does not provide
serializable execution it's doing
还有其他的事情，所以当我们在思考如果或
something else and so while we're
thinking through what would happen if or
如果始终违背这些AHA将会发生什么，这是仅有的两个
what would happen if will always be
against these AHA these are the only two
合法的结果，我们最好做一些能够产生彼此的事情
legal results we better be doing
something that produces one or the other
有趣的是，有不止一种可能的结果取决于
it's interesting to note that there's
more than one possible result depending
根据实际订单，如果您在
on the actual order you if you you
submit these two transactions at the
同时您不知道是t1 t2还是t2 t1，所以您必须
same time you don't know whether it's
gonna be t1 t2 or t2 t1 so you have to
愿意期待不止一种可能的法律结果，并且如您所愿
be willing to expect more than one
possible legal result and as you have
更多或同时运行的事务更加复杂
more or transactions running
concurrently a more complicated there
可能有很多很多可能不同的正确结果
may be many many possible different
correct results that are all
可序列化，因为这里有很多订单可以用来完成此任务
serializable because of many many orders
here that could be used to fulfill this
需求还可以，所以现在我们有了正确性的定义，甚至
requirement okay so now that we have a
definition of correctness and we even
知道所有可能的结果是什么我们可以问几个问题
know what all the possible results are
we can ask a few questions so few
关于如何执行的假设问题，例如，假设
what-if questions about how these could
execute so for example suppose that the
系统实际执行此操作的方式是它开始了事务2，
way the system actually executed this
was that it started transaction 2 and
读完X之后就达到了
got as far as
just after reading X and then
交易一在这一点上运行，然后在交易一完成后
transaction one ran at this point and
then after transaction one finished
现在继续执行交易，结果与其他交易不同
transaction to continue executing now it
turns out in with different other
比这实际上可能合法的交易，但在这里我们要
transactions than this that might
actually be legal but here we want to
知道这是否合法，所以我们想知道天哪，我们是否真的以这种方式执行
know if it's legal so we're wondering
gosh if we actually executed that way
我们会得到什么结果，它们是否与这两个方法中的任何一个相同，如果
what results will we get and are they
the same as either of these two well if
我们在这里执行事务一，那么t1将看到值10 t2将看到
we execute transaction one here then t1
is gonna see value 10 t2 is gonna see
Y递减后的值，因此t1将为10 t2将为9，这是什么
the value after decrementing Y so t1
will be 10 t2 will be 9 and what this
打印将是10 9，而这两个输出都不是，所以这意味着
print will be 10 9 and that's neither of
these two outputs here so that means
以我刚刚绘制的方式执行，无法序列化，因此不会
executing in this way that I just drew
is not serializable it would not be
法律上另一个有趣的问题是，如果我们开始执行交易该怎么办
legal another interesting question is
what if we started executing transaction
1，我们就到达了第一个广告之后，然后所有
1 and we got as far as just after the
first ad and then at that point all the
事务2在这里执行，因此这意味着X是值
transaction 2 executed right here so
that would mean at this point X is value
11事务2将读取为1110现在打印1110，而1110不是其中之一
11 the transaction 2 would read 1110 now
print 1110 and 1110 is not one of these
两个合法值，因此对于这两个而言，执行也是不合法的
two legal values so this execution is
also not legal for these two
交易
transactions
所以可序列化可序列化之所以流行且有用的原因
so the reason why serializable
serializability is a popular and useful
定义交易正确执行的含义
definition of what it means for
transactions to be correct for execution
正确的交易是对程序员来说这是一个非常简单的模型
of transactions to be correct is that
it's a very easy model for programmers
您可以编写复杂的交易而不必担心其他事情
you can write complicated transactions
without having to worry about what else
可能正在系统中运行，可能还有很多其他交易
may be running in the system there may
be lots of other transactions may be
使用与您可能正在阅读的日期相同的日期尝试读取和写入它
using the same date as you may be
reading trying to read and write it at
同时可能会有失败的人知道，但是这里的保证是
the same time there might be failures
who knows but the guarantee here is that
就像没有其他事情发生一样写交易是安全的，因为
it's safe to write your transactions as
if nothing else was happening because
最终结果必须好像您的交易是在
the final results have to be as if your
transaction was executed by itself in
这是一次非常简单的非常好的编程模型
this one-at-a-time order which is a very
simple very nice programming model it's
还不错，这个定义允许真正并行执行事务
also nice that this definition allows
truly parallel execution of transactions
只要他们不使用相同的数据，我们就会在这里遇到麻烦，因为
as long as they don't use the same data
so we run into trouble here because
这两个事务都读取x和y，但是如果它们正在使用
these two transactions are both reading
x and y but if they were using
完全不相交的数据库记录，他们可能会得出这个定义
completely disjoint database records
they could it turns out this definition
允许您构建一个数据库系统，该系统将执行要使用的事务
allows you to build a database system
that would execute transactions to use
如果您是分片系统，则可以完全并行地分离数据
disjoint data completely in parallel and
if you are a sharded system which is
我们今天要处理的数据与其他数据有关
what we're sort of working up to today
with the data different data is on
在不同的机器上，您可以获得真正的并行加速，因为
different machines you can get true
parallel speed-up because maybe one
事务在第一台机器上的第一个分片中执行Spira，另一台机器上执行
transaction executes Spira in the first
shard on the first machine and the other
在第二台机器上并行运行，因此这里有机会
in parallel on the second machine so
there are opportunities here for for
在研究如何实现可序列化事务之前，性能良好
good performance before I dig into how
to implement serializable transactions
还有一点我想提出来，事实证明，其中之一
there's one more small point I want to
bring up it turns out that one of the
我们需要处理的事情是交易可能出于某种原因
things we need to be able to cope with
is that transactions may for one reason
或另一个基本上失败或决定失败的
or another
basically fail or decide to fail in the
事务的中间，通常称为中止，您知道
middle of the transaction and this is
usually called an abort and you know for
我们需要准备好许多交易系统来处理哦，会发生什么
many transaction systems we need to be
prepared to handle Oh what should happen
如果事务试图访问不存在或除以的记录
if a transaction tries to access a
record that doesn't exist or divides by
零或您可能知道，因为某些事务实施方案使用了
zero or maybe you know since some
transaction implementation schemes use
锁定可能导致事务锁定死锁，并且唯一的方法是
locking maybe a transaction causes a
locking deadlock and the only way to
打破僵局是为了杀死一个或多个交易之一
break the deadlock is to kill one of one
or more of the transactions this
参与僵局，所以其中之一将是
participating in the deadlock so one of
the things that's going to be kind of
挂在后台并且会出现是应对的必要
hanging in the background and will come
up is the necessity of coping with
中间突然决定无法进行的交易
transactions that all of a sudden in the
middle decide they just cannot proceed
你可能知道他们完成一些工作并开始工作之后
and you know maybe really in the middle
after they've done some work and started
修改东西，我们需要能够从这些交易中撤出
modifying things we need to be able to
kind of back out of these transactions
并撤消他们所做的任何修改
and undo any modifications they've made
all right
这些资产交易的实施策略
the implementation strategy for
transactions for these asset
交易我将分为两大部分，但同时讨论
transactions I'm gonna split into two
big pieces but and talk about both of
他们是讲座中的主要主题第一个重要的实施主题是
them the main topics in the lecture the
first big implementation topic is
并发控制，这是我们用来提供可序列化性的主要工具
concurrency control this is the main
tool we use to provide serializability
当前或隔离，因此并发控制偏差
the current or isolation so concurrency
control bias
通过将其与可能尝试使用的其他并发事务隔离
by its isolation from other concurrent
transactions that might be trying to use
我提到的相同数据和其他重要部分是原子提交，这是
the same data and the other big pieces I
mentioned is atomic commit and this is
有什么可以帮助我们应对这种可能性的呢？
what's going to help us deal with the
possibility that oh yeah this
执行一个很长的事务，可以将其修改为X，然后将所有
transactions executing a long and it's
may be modified X and then all of a
突然出现故障，其中一台服务器参与其中，但其他服务器
sudden there's a failure and one of the
server's involved but other servers that
可能实际上是在交易的其他部分，如果x和y是
were maybe actually in other parts of
the transaction that is if x and y are
在不同的机器上，即使有部分机器，我们也需要能够恢复
in different machines we need to be able
to recover even if there's a partial
仅有部分机器发生故障，交易不顺利，交易量很大
failure of only some of the machines the
transactions running off and the big
人们为此使用的工具是这个原子提交，您会说的没错，所以
tool people use for that is this atomic
commit you'll talk about all right so
首先是并发控制，实际上有两类两种主要方法
first concurrency control there's really
two classes two major approaches to
并发控制在课程中，我将同时讨论这两个问题
concurrency control I'll talk about both
during the course if they're just mean
策略第一种策略是悲观主义者，通常被称为悲观主义者
strategies the first strategy is a
pessimistic usually called pessimist
悲观的并发控制，这通常是锁定，我们都完成了
pessimistic concurrency control and this
is usually locking we've all done
在go程序的上下文中锁定实验室，从而证明数据库
locking in the labs in the context of go
program so it turns out databases
事务处理系统也使用锁定，这里的想法是U是
transaction processing systems also used
locking and the idea here is U is the
同样，您在交易使用任何
same as well you're quite familiar with
this that before transaction uses any
数据，它需要获取对该数据的锁定以及其他一些事务
data it needs to acquire a lock on that
data and if some other transactions
已经使用了该数据的锁将被保留，我们必须等待之前
already using the data the lock will be
held and we'll have to wait before we
可以获取锁以等待其他事务完成并且悲观
can acquire the lock wait for the other
transaction to finish and in pessimistic
系统，如果存在锁定冲突，其他人将导致锁定
systems if there's locking conflicts
somebody else has the lock it'll cause
延迟，所以您在某种程度上将性能视为正确性
delays so you're sort of treating
performance for correctness the other
主要方法是乐观方法
main approach is optimistic approaches
这里的基本思想是，您不必担心是否还有其他问题
the basic idea here is you don't worry
about whether maybe some other
事务与您刚去时同时读取或写入数据
transactions reading or writing the data
at the same time as you you just go
前进，做任何您会做的读写操作，尽管通常会
ahead and do whatever reads and writes
you're gonna do although typically into
某种临时区域，然后仅在结束时去检查是否
some sort of temporary area and then
only at the end you go and check whether
实际上也许其他交易可能会干扰，如果
actually maybe some other transaction
might have been interfering and if
现在没有其他交易了，您再也不必经历任何交易了
there's no other transaction now you're
done and you never had to go through any
取出锁的开销或权重是合理的
of the overhead or weighting of taking
out locks the locks are reasonably
昂贵的操作，但是如果其他人正在修改数据
expensive to manipulate but if somebody
else was modifying the data in a
在您同时存在冲突的方式时，您必须中止
conflicting way at the same time you
were then you have to abort that
交易，我们尝试使用这种形式的缩写
transaction and we try and the
abbreviation for this is often
乐观的并发控制
optimistic concurrency control um it
turns out that under different
在这两种策略中，一种可能比另一种更快
circumstances these two strategies one
can be faster than the other
如果冲突非常频繁，您可能实际上想使用
if conflicts are very frequent you
probably actually want to use
悲观的并发控制不是因为经常发生冲突
pessimistic concurrency control not
because of conflicts are frequent you're
会因为冲突而大量流产
gonna get a lot of aborts due to
conflicts for optimistic seems if
复杂性远比乐观并发控制可以更快
complex are rare than optimistic
concurrency control can be faster
因为它完全避免了锁定开销，今天将成为一切
because it completely avoids locking
overhead today will be all about
悲观并发控制，然后在特定农场中的某些后来的论文中
pessimistic concurrency control and then
some later paper in particular farm in a
几个星期，我们将处理一个乐观的计划，所以今天
couple weeks we'll deal with an
optimistic scheme okay so today talking
关于悲观方案，基本上是指锁定，尤其是
about pessimistic schemes refers
basically to locking and in particular
今天的阅读是关于两相锁定，这是最
for today the reading was about
two-phase locking which is the most
普通锁
common type of locking
两阶段锁定交易的想法是，交易将
and the idea in two-phase locking for
transactions is that transactions gonna
使用诸如X＆Y之类的一堆Records和我们的示例，第一个规则是
use a bunch of Records like X&Y and our
example the first rule is that you
在使用日期之前获取锁，我们正在读取或写入的任何数据
acquire a lock before using date any
piece of data we're reading or writing
任何记录和交易的第二条规则是交易必须
any record and the second rule for
transactions is that a transaction must
持有它获得的任何锁，直到它提交或中止之后才被允许
hold any locks it acquires until after
it commits or aborts you're not allowed
要放弃交易中间的锁，您必须全部持有
to give up locks in the middle of the
transaction you have to hold them all
您只能积累它们，直到完成为止
you can only accumulate them until
you're done until after you're done so
直到菲比这样做，这是两阶段锁定的阶段
until Phoebe done so this is two-phase
locking the phases are the phases which
我们获得锁，然后逐步进入锁，直到完成
we acquire locks and then phase in which
we just hold onto them until we're done
因此，对于两相锁定，可以了解为什么锁定可以正常工作
so for two phase locking to sort of see
why locking works your typical locking
系统很好，有很多变化，典型的锁定系统与
systems well there's a lot of variation
typical locking systems associate a
数据库中的每个记录都有单独的锁，每个表中的每一行都用于
separate lock with each record in the
database with each row in each table for
示例，尽管它们可以更粗粒度地进行，但这些事务开始
example although they can be more more
coarse-grained these transactions start
说不持有锁，说交易一开始就不持有
out holding no locks let's say
transaction one starts out holding no
它在第一次使用X之前会锁定，所以我必须使用它必须获取
locks when it first uses X before so
I'll have to use it it has to acquire
X上的锁，它可能必须等待，并且在它第一次使用Y时获得
the lock on X and it may have to wait
and when it first uses Y it acquires
另一个将Y锁完成后将其锁定
another lock the lock on Y when it
finishes after it's done becoming these
如果我们同时运行这两个交易，它们基本上都是
both if we ran both these transactions
at the same time they're gonna basically
争夺X上的锁定，并且其中任何一个都设法获得锁定
race to get the lock on X and whichever
of them gets the managed to get the lock
首先在X上它将继续进行并完成并提交
on X first it will proceed and finish
and commit meantime the other
未能成功锁定X的事务，它将查看是否
transaction that didn't manage to get
the lock on X first it's going to see if
您在等待之前，使用OA口音可以做什么
you're waiting before it what you does
anything with accent OA can acquire the
锁定，因此事务2实际上首先获得了锁定
lock so transaction 2 actually got the
lock first
你会得到X的值得到y的值cuz交易之一还没有
you would get the value of X get the
value of y cuz transaction one hasn't
在这一点上得到还没有锁定Y它将打印并完成，
gotten at this point hasn't locked Y yet
it'll print and it will finish and
释放它的锁，然后交易一才可以获取
release its locks and only then
transaction one will be able to acquire
X上的锁，如您所见，基本上会强制执行序列订单，因为
the lock on X and as you can see that
basically forces a serial order because
在这种情况下，它强制执行命令T两个，然后当T两个完成时
it forced in this case it force the
order T two and then when T two finishes
只有T 1，所以它显式地强制执行顺序，从而导致
only then T 1 so with it's explicitly
forcing an order which causes the that
执行以遵循您真正知道的可序列化性定义
execution to follow the definition of
serializability that you know really is
执行T 2直到完成，然后才执行T 1，这样我们才能正确执行
executing T 2 to completion and only
then T 1 so we do get correct execution
好的，所以一个问题是，为什么您需要按住锁直到
all right so one question is why you
need to hold the locks until the
交易已完全完成，您可能会认为您可以持有一笔
transactions completely finished you
might think that you could just hold a
在实际使用数据时锁定，这样会更有效率
lock while you are actually using the
data and that would be more efficient
的确，那就是您知道也许只在这段时间内持有锁
and indeed it would that is you know
maybe only hold the lock for the period
t2实际上正在查看记录X的时间，或者可能仅持有锁
of time in which t2 is actually looking
at record X or maybe only hold the lock
在X上执行添加操作期间，然后立即释放
on X here for the duration of the add
operation and then immediately release
它，在这种情况下，如果我们进行交易怎么办立即释放了
it and in that case that what if we
transaction one immediately released a
遵守此规则当然可以将X锁定在那里
lock on X there there by disobeying this
rule of course but if it immediately
释放X上的锁，然后事务2可能可以开始一点
release the lock on X then transaction
two might be able to start a little bit
我们越早获得更多的并发性和更高的性能，因此这条规则
earlier we get more concurrency more
higher performance so this rule
绝对您知道对性能不利，因此我们要确保它
definitely you know bad for performance
so we want to make pretty sure that it's
这是正确性所必需的
it's good for that's required for
correctness
因此，如果事务确实在最早的时候就释放了锁，那将不会发生
so what won't happen if transactions did
actually release locks as early as
可能的话，假设t2在这里读X，然后
possible
so suppose t2 here reads X and then
立即释放对X的锁定，该锁定将允许t1，因为目前
immediately releases this lock on X that
would allow t1 since at now at this
t2执行中的点不持有任何锁，因为它只是释放了它
point in the execution t2 doesn't hold
any locks because it's just released it
非法释放X上的锁，因为它没有锁，这意味着t1可以
illegally release the lock on X since it
holds a no locks that means t1 could
完全在这里执行，我们从那之前就已经知道
completely execute right here and we
already knew from from before that this
交织不正确，因为它不会产生这两个输出
interleaving is not correct as it
doesn't produce either these two outputs
类似地，如果t1向X加完后释放了X的锁定，
similarly if if t1 released this lock on
X after finished adding one to X that
将允许所有t2滑入此处，我们也从那之前知道
would allow all of t2 to slip in right
here and we know also from before that
导致非法结果
that results in in illegal results
还有另外一种问题，可能与释放锁有关
there's a an additional kind of problem
that can come up with releasing locks
修改数据后，如果t1将释放X的锁定，则可能允许t2
after modifying data if t1 were to
release the lock on X it might allow t2
来查看X的修改版本，在这里向其添加1和
to see the modified version of X here to
see the X after adding 1 to it and to
打印该输出，然后在打印增量后让tteyuu完成
print that output and then for tteyuu to
complete after printing the incremented
如果事务1在该点之后中止，则x的值可能是因为
value of x if transaction one were to
abort after that point maybe because
银行余额Y不存在，或者银行债券Y存在，但其余额为
bank balance Y doesn't exist or maybe
bank bonds Y exists but its balance is
零，您知道我们不允许银行结余减少0，因为
zero and you know we're not allowed to
decrement 0 for bank balances because
这是透支的，所以t1可能会修改X然后中止，并且中止的一部分必须
that's an overdraft so t1 might modify X
then abort and part of the abort has to
撤消其对X的更新，以保持原子性以及这将是什么
be undoing its update to X in order to
maintain atomicity and what that would
意思是如果它释放了锁，那就是事务2会看到这种情况
mean if it released the locks is that
transaction 2 would have seen this sort
的幻像值11消失了，因为t1中止了，您会看到一个
of phantom value of 11 that went away
because t1 aborted you would have seen a
根据规则永远不存在的价值，因为那时
value that according to the rules never
existed right because then the
事务1中止，就好像它不存在一样，因此这意味着
transaction 1 aborts then it's as if it
never existed and so that means the
来自t2的结果最好是好像t2完全没有t1自己运行，但是如果
results from t2 had better be as if t2
ran by itself without t1 at all but if
它看到的增量实际上是要为X 11 10打印11
it sees the increment that it's gonna
print 11 for X 11 10 actually which is
鉴于t1并非真正与数据库中的任何状态都不对应
just doesn't correspond to any state in
the database given that t1 didn't really
完全可以，所以这就是为什么要避免的两个危险
complete okay so that's why those are
two dangers that are averted due to
违规序列化的能力可以避免，因为事务持有
violations serialize ability that are
averted because transactions hold the
锁定，直到他们做完有关这些规则的进一步操作为止
locks until they're done a further thing
to note about these rules or that it's
他们很容易产生死锁，所以例如您知道我们有两个
very easy for them to produce deadlock
so you know for example if we have two
事务之一读取记录ax，读取记录y
transactions one of them reads record ax
and reads record y
而另一个事务读取Y，然后读取X，这只是一个死锁，如果
and the other transaction reads Y and
then X that's that's just a deadlock if
他们在同一时间运行，每个人都在记录上获得此锁定
they run at the same time they each of
them gets this lock on the record it
首先阅读它们直到交易完成才释放，所以他们都坐下来
first read they don't release till the
transactions finish so they both sit
在那里等待其他交易持有的锁，除非
there waiting for the lock that's held
by the other transaction and unless the
数据库做了一些聪明的事
database does something clever which it
will
他们将永远陷入僵局，实际上交易有各种策略
they'll deadlock forever and in fact
transactions have various strategies
包括跟踪周期或超时，以检测它们是否已进入
including tracing cycles or timeouts in
order to detect that they've gone into
数据库将中止这两个事务之一并撤消的情况
the situation the database will abort
one of these two transactions and undo
所有的变化，就像从未发生过的交易一样，所以
all its changes and act as if that
transaction that never occurred okay so
这是具有两阶段锁定的并发控制，这仅仅是
that's concurrency control with
two-phase locking and this is just
到目前为止，完全标准的数据库行为，并且一次都相同
completely standard database behavior so
far and it's the same in a single
机器数据库和分布式数据库
machine databases as it will be and
distributed databases that are a little
对我们有更多的兴趣，但我们的下一个话题实际上是针对
more interest to us but our next topic
is a little is actually specific to
总体上构建支持以下事务的数据库或存储系统：
building databases or storage systems in
general that support transactions on
分布式设置，可将数据拆分到多台计算机上，因此现在
distributed setting that is splitting
the data over multiple machines so now
主题是如何建立分布式分布式事务以及
the topic is how to build distributed
distributed transactions and in
特别是如何应对失败，更具体地说是部分
particular how to cope with failures and
more specifically the kind of partial
您经常在分布式系统中看到的众多服务器之一发生故障
failures of just one of many servers
that you often see in distributed
分布式交易之外的其他系统，我们担心如何
systems so beyond distributed
transactions and we're worried about how
他们的行为是要确保它们可序列化，并且还具有
they behave you make sure they're
serializable and also have sort of
即使面对失败，全有或全无的广告Amissah T
all-or-nothing ad Amissah T even in the
face of failures so
你知道我你知道这看起来像什么，我们可能有两个
you know I you know what the way this
looks like is that we may have two
服务器，我们得到了一个服务器，也许它在我们的银行中存储了记录X，我们
servers and we got server one and maybe
it stores record X in our bank and we
有两个服务器，也许是商店记录Y，所以它们都以
have server two and maybe it's stores
record Y so they all start out with
值10，我们需要运行这两个交易，即交易1
value 10 and we need to run these two
transactions that transaction 1 of
当然会同时修改x和y，所以现在我们需要发送消息，数据库是
course modifies both x and y so now we
need to send messages the database is
说哦，请递增X请递减Y，但是如果我们
saying oh please increment X please
decrement Y but it would be easy if we
不小心进入我们告诉服务器1增加的情况
weren't careful to get into a situation
where we had told server 1 to increase
X的余额，但随后发生故障，也许客户端发送了
the balance for X but then something
failed maybe the client sending the
请求或服务器服务器-保持Y失败或其他原因，
requests or maybe server the server -
that's holding Y fails or something and
我们从未设法正确进行第二次更新，所以一个问题是失败
we never managed to do the second update
right so that's one problem is failure
某个地方可能会将交易减少一半，如果我们不这样做
somewhere may sort of cut the
transaction in half and if we're not
谨慎地导致只有一半的交易实际生效
如果X参与交易，即使没有崩溃也可能发生
this can happen even without crashes if
X does its part in the transaction it
可能是服务器到服务器上实际将请求发送到
could be that over on server-to-server
to actually gets the request to
递减银行帐户y，但服务器2可能发现此银行帐户
不存在或也许确实存在，并且当它不能平衡时余额已经为0
doesn't exist or maybe it does exist and
it's balance is already 0 when it can't
被减少，因此它不能完成交易的一部分，但是X看起来有
be decrease and so it can't do its part
of the transaction but X look has
已经完成了交易的一部分，所以这是一个需要解决的问题
already done its part of the transaction
so that's a problem that needs to be
处理，所以我们想要的财产是我之前提到的
dealt with so the the property we want
as I mentioned before is that all the
系统的各个部分，或者系统的所有部分都应该做
pieces of the system either all the
pieces of the system should do their
交易的一部分或没有权利，所以您知道我们所从事的事情
part of the transaction or none right so
you know the kind of the thing we
违反这里是什么原子性来防止崩溃或失败，其中原子性
violated here is what atomicity against
crashes versus failure where atomicity
是我们尝试执行的交易的所有部分的全部还是全部？
is all or not all parts all parts of the
transaction that we're trying to execute
或全都不用，对于您来说，我们将要提供的解决方案是
or none of them and for you more the
kind of solution we're going to be
看看是原子承诺原子承诺协议和一般的
looking at is atomic commitments atomic
commit protocols and the general kind of
原子提交协议的味道是您有一堆计算机
flavor of atomic commit protocols is
that you have a bunch of computers
他们都在做更大的任务和原子提交的不同部分
they're all doing different parts of
some larger task and the atomic commit
协议将帮助计算机确定要么全部
protocol is gonna help the computers
decide that either they're all going to
他们是不是他们都有能力发挥自己的作用，他们实际上会做
do they're they're all capable of doing
their part and they're actually gonna do
它或某些地方出了问题，他们都同意哦
it or something has gone wrong and
they're all going to agree that oh
他们实际上都不是他们要去做的事
they're actually none of them are gonna
do their part of the whatever the
总体任务是，最大的挑战当然是如何应对各种挑战
overall task is and the big challenges
are of course how to cope with various
故障机器故障消息丢失，事实证明
failures machine failures loss of
messages and it'll turn out that
表现也很难做好
performance is also a little bit
difficult to do a good job with the
我们将要研究的特定协议，该协议在
specific protocol we're gonna look at
and is the protocol explained in a
今天阅读我们的两阶段提交
reading for today our two-phase commit
这是一个原子承诺协议
this is an atomic commitment protocol
分布式数据库和各种其他数据库都使用
and this is used both by distributed
databases and also by all kinds of other
最初看起来可能不像传统数据库的分布式系统
distributed systems that might not have
first looked like traditional databases
一般设置是假设我们以一种或另一种方式完成任务
the general setting is we assume that
that in one way or another the task we
需要执行的任务分散在多个服务器上，每个服务器都需要执行
need to perform is split up over
multiple servers each of which needs to
每个人都做一些不同的部分，例如，因为我被定为
do some part a different part each one
of them so for example because I'm set
我在这里显示的是其中真正分散的数据，因此
up I showed here in which the it's
really the data that split up and so the
任务被分割成递增的X和递减的YD
tasks being split up our incrementing X
and decrementing Y D we're going to
假设有一台驱动交易的计算机称为
assume that there's one computer that's
driving the transaction called the
交易协调员有很多安排交易方式的方法
transaction coordinator there's lots of
ways of arranging how the transaction
协调员介入，但我们将其想象成一台计算机，
coordinator steps in but we'll just
imagine it as a computer that is
实际运行交易时，交易协调员只有一台计算机
actually running the transaction there's
one computer the transaction coordinator
那就是执行类似puts和
that's that's executing the sort of code
for the transaction like the puts and
获取和添加，它将消息发送到保存
the gets and the adds and it sends
messages to the computers that hold the
需要实际执行不同部分的不同数据，因此
different pieces of data that need to
actually execute the different parts so
对于我们的设置，我们将有一台交易协调器的计算机
for our setup we're going to have one
computer of the transaction coordinator
并且将由这些服务器一和服务器二进行X＆Y交易
and it's going to be these server one
and server two that hold X&Y transaction
协调员，我们将向服务器发送一条消息，说哦，请增加X
coordinator we'll send a message to
server one saying oh please increment X
向服务器Y发送一条消息，说哦，请递减Y，然后会有
send a message to server Y saying oh
please decrement Y and then there'll be
更多消息，以确保它们两者都执行或不执行
more messages in order to make sure that
either they both do it or neither than
做到这一点，这是两阶段提交将某些内容保留在后面的地方
do it and that's where two-phase commit
steps in something to keep in the back
您的想法是，在整个系统中可能会有许多不同的交易
your mind is that in the full system
there may be many different transactions
同时运行和许多事务协调器
running concurrently and many
transaction coordinators
执行自己的交易，因此这里的各方都需要
sort of executing their own transactions
and so the various parties here need to
跟踪哦，您知道这是某某交易的消息
keep track of oh you know this is a
message for such-and-such a transaction
并保持这些状态，结果这些服务器将
and where they keep state like these
turns out these servers are going to
例如，维护表两个块，它们保持所需状态
maintain table two blocks for example
and they keep state like that they need
跟踪哦，这是为交易而持有的锁17
to keep track of oh this is a lock
that's being held for transactions 17 so
有一个交易ID的概念，我只是假设，尽管您知道
there's a notion of transaction IDs and
I'm just gonna assume although you know
我并没有真正表明系统中的每条消息都带有
I'm not actually show it that every
message in the system is tagged with the
具有适用于该交易的交易的唯一交易ID的交易，以及
transaction with the unique transaction
ID of the transaction it applies to and
这些ID由交易协调员在交易开始时选择
these IDs are chosen by the transaction
coordinator when the transaction starts
交易协调员将发出哦，这是交易消息
the transaction coordinator will send
out oh this is a message for transaction
1995年，它将在此处保留有关交易的所有状态，将被标记
1995 and it'll keep all its state here
about the transaction will be tagged
95和不同参与者中的各种表格
with 95 and the various tables in the
different participants in the
交易将使用交易ID进行标记，这是另一个
transaction will be tagged with the
transaction IDs and so that's another
术语，我们得到了交易协调员，然后
piece of terminology we got the
transaction coordinator and then the
执行事务的其他服务器称为参与者
other servers that are doing parts of
the transaction are called participants
好吧，让我画出两阶段提交
all right
so let me draw out the two-phase commit
协议示例执行，因此这是PC的两相缩写
protocol example execution so this is
abbreviate this to PC for two-phase
承诺涉及的各方是交易协调员，我们将
commit the parties involved are the
transaction coordinator and we'll just
说有两个参与者，你知道也许我们正在执行
say there's two participants that is you
know maybe we're executing the
接下来显示的事务以及为什么没有不同的服务器，也许我们有
transactions I've shown next and why
aren't different servers maybe we've got
参与者a和参与者b这是两个保存数据的不同服务器
participant a and participant B these
are two different servers holding data
所以交易协调员正在运行整个交易
so the transaction coordinator it's
running the whole transaction it's it's
会发送看跌期权并到达a和B告诉他们您知道读取的值
gonna send puts and gets to a and B to
tell them to you know read the value of
x或y或将一个加到X，所以我们将在树的开头看到
x or y or add one to X so we're going to
see at the beginning of the tree
事务协调器正在发送的操作，例如可能是获取
action that the transaction coordinator
is sending for example maybe a get
向Trent参与者a请求，它得到答复，然后也许发送
requests to Trent participant a and it
gets a reply and then maybe it sends
如果有可能，我可能会看到很长的序列
that put for whatever I might see a long
sequence of these if there's a
复杂的交易，然后交易协调员结束
complicated transaction then when
transaction coordinator gets to the end
交易并想要提交并知道释放所有交易
of the transaction and wants to commit
it and be able to you know release all
这些锁并使交易结果对外界可见，并且
those locks and make the transactions
results visible to the outside world and
可能是回复客户或人类用户，所以他们假设有一种
maybe reply to a client or a human user
so they were assuming there's a sort of
外部客户或人员说，哦，请运行此交易，
external client or human that said oh
please run this transaction and it's
等待响应，然后我们才能执行任何事务协调
waiting for a response before we can do
any of that the transaction coordinate
协调员必须确保所有不同的参与者都可以实际
coordinator has to make sure that all
the different participants can actually
尽自己的职责，尤其是如果有任何看跌期权
do their part of the transaction and in
particular if there were any puts in the
交易，我们需要确保正在做这些的参与者
transaction we need to make sure that
the participants who are doing those
推杆实际上仍然能够执行推杆，因此为了发现
puts well are actually still capable of
doing the puts so in order to find that
交易协调员将准备消息发送给所有
out the transaction coordinator sends
prepare messages to all of the
参与者，所以我们将同时发送配对消息到a和B
participants so we're going to send pair
messages to both a and B
当a或B收到准备者消息时，您知道他们知道
and when a or B would receive a preparer
message you know they know the
交易即将完成，但尚未结束
transaction is nearing completion but
not not over yet
他们查看自己的状态并决定他们是否真正有能力
they look at their state and decide
whether they are actually able to
完成您知道的交易，也许他们需要中止交易以打破僵局
complete the transaction you know maybe
they needed to abort it break a deadlock
也许他们坠毁了，我们开始了，但是你们之间知道他们什么时候做的
or maybe they've crashed and we started
but between you know when they did the
现在是最后一次手术，他们已经完全忘记了
last operation are now and they've
completely forgotten about the
交易并且无法完成交易，所以您知道A和B的状态，
transaction and can't complete it so a
and B you know look at their state and
说哦，我将能够或我将无法执行此交易
say oh I'm going to be able to or I'm
not gonna be able to do this transaction
他们回答是或否
and they respond with either yes or no
因此交易协调员正在等待来自这些的赞成或反对表决
so the transaction coordinator is
waiting for these yes or no votes from
每个参与者，如果所有人都说“是”，则交易可以提交
each of the participants if they all say
yes then the transaction can commit
事务可以提交且事务协调器没有错
nothing goes wrong the transaction can
commit and the transaction coordinator
向每个参与者发送提交消息，然后
sends out a commit message to each of
the participants and then the
参与者通常会在回覆中说，是的，我们现在知道
participants usually reply with an
acknowledgement saying yes we now know
结果就是所谓的技术学，所以他们都交易
the outcome this is called the echnology
all right so they all transaction
协调员，因为我准备者是否所有参与者都同意，如果
coordinator since I preparers if all the
participants say yes it can commit if
其中任何一个人甚至一个人都说不，实际上我无法完成此任务
anyone in any of them even a single one
says no actually I cannot complete this
交易是因为我失败或出现不一致的情况
transaction because I had a failure or
there was an inconsistency like a
缺少记录，我什至必须中止一个参与者说不
missing record and I have to abort even
a single participant says no at this
然后交易协调员不会提交，它将发出一轮
point then the transaction coordinator
won't commit it'll send out a round of
中止消息，哎呀，请以两种方式撤回该交易
abort messages saying oops please
retract this transaction either way the
在提交两件事之后，我们感兴趣的事情发生了
after the commit sort of to two things
happen of interest to us
一是交易协调员将铸造任何交易输出
one is the transaction coordinator will
mint whatever the transactions output is
向要求它的客户或人员说，看，哦，是的，交易
to the client or human that requested it
and say look oh yes the transactions
完成，所以现在，如果它不中止提交，则可以持久使用
finish and so now if it didn't abort a
committed it's durable
另一个有趣的事情是，为了遵守这些锁定规则，
the other interesting thing is that in
order to obey these locking rules the
参与者在看到提交或中止并且确实有序时解锁
participants unlock when they see either
commit or an abort and indeed in order
为了遵守两个阶段锁定规则，每个参与者都锁定了它读取的任何数据
to obey the two phase locking rule each
participant locked any data that it read
作为完成交易的一部分，因此我们在想象中
as part of doing its part of the
transaction so we're imagining that in
每个参与者都有一张与存储在以下位置的数据相关的锁表
each participant there's a table of the
locks associated with the data stored at
该参与者和参与者在这些表中锁定了一些东西
that participant and the participant
sort of lock things in those tables
记住哦，这是您知道该记录被锁定的那段数据
remember oh this is you know this piece
of data this record is locked for
事务二十九，最后提交或中止返回版本
transaction twenty nine and one finally
the commit or abort comes back versions
行动29，参与者解锁该数据，然后其他
action twenty-nine the participant
unlocks that data and then other
交易可以使用，因此我们可能必须在这里等待，并且此解锁可能会解除阻止
transactions can use so we may have to
wait here and this unlock may unblock
其他事务实际上是可序列化机制的一部分，因此您
other transactions that's really part of
the serializability machinery so you
到目前为止，基本上知道这是正确的原因是
know so far the reason why this is
correct basically is that the if
每个人都遵循这个协议，没有失败，然后两个
everybody's following this protocol
there's no failures then the two
参与者只有在他们都承诺的情况下才承诺，如果我他们不能承诺，则
participants only commit if both of them
commit and if I them can't commit if
我必须让他们中止然后他们都中止，所以我们得到他们要么都做
I've them has to abort then they both
abort so we get that either they all do
它或它们都不做，导致我们想要此原子性结果
it or none of them do it result that we
wanted the atomicity result with this
到目前为止，我们都没有考虑失败，所以现在我们的工作是
protocol so far without without thinking
about failures and so now our job is to
在我们脑海中思考各种不同类型的失败，
think through in our head all sort of
the different kinds of failures that
可能会发生，并找出协议是否仍然提供原子性
might occur and figure out whether the
protocol still provides atomicity either
面对这些失败以及我们必须如何应对
both do it or neither do it in the face
of these failures and how we have to
调整或扩展协议以使其执行正确的操作，因此
adjust or extend the protocol in order
to cause it to do the right thing so the
我要考虑的第一件事是崩溃和
first thing I want
consider is what it be crashes and
重新启动我的意思是电源故障或某种原因
restarts
I mean power failure or something be
只是有些突然停止执行，然后恢复供电，
just some suddenly stops executing and
then powers restored and it's brought
回到生活并运行一些可能的某种恢复软件作为
back to life and run some maybe some
sort of recovery software as part of the
交易处理系统确实有两种情况我们必须
transaction processing system well
there's really two scenarios we have to
担心一个是B在升序之前可能已经崩溃了，是的。
worry about one is B might have crashed
before ascending it's yes message back
所以B在发送回yes消息之前崩溃了，所以它从没说过yes
so B crash before sending its yes
message back then it never said yes so
交易协调员可能没有承诺或将要
the transaction coordinator couldn't
possibly have committed or be about to
提交，因为它必须等待所有参与者的同意，以便B可以
commit because it has to wait for a yes
from all participants so if B can
说服自己它不可能发送回是
convince itself that it could not
possibly have sent a yes back that is a
在发送“是”之前崩溃，则B有权单方面中止
crash before sending the yes then B is
entitled to unilaterally abort the
交易本身，并忘记它，因为它知道交易
transaction itself and forget about it
because it knows the transaction
协调员可能无法提交，因此[音乐]
coordinator can't possibly commit it so
[Music]
您知道实现此可能性的多种方法是
there's you know a number of ways of
implementing this one possibility is
所有有关尚未达到此目的的交易的信息
that all of these information about
transactions that haven't reached this
点在内存中，它只是丢失了，B崩溃并重新启动，因此B不会
point is in memory and it simply lost it
B crashes and reboots so B just won't
对尚未回传的交易一无所知
know anything about transactions that
haven't haven't sent yes back yet and
然后，如果交易协调员将准备消息发送给参与者
then if the transaction coordinator
sends a prepare message to a participant
对交易一无所知，因为它之前崩溃了
that doesn't know anything about the
transaction because it crashed before
发送是，各方会说不，我不能同意你
sending yes the the parties will say no
no I cannot possibly agree to that you
知道请中止
know please abort
可以，但是当然B可能会在发送回yes后崩溃了，这有点
okay but of course maybe B crashed after
sending a yes back so that's a little
更加棘手，所以不是在飞机坠毁中这不是B做好准备的原因
more tricky so wasn't in the crash
this wasn't a B gets a prepare its it's
很高兴它说是的，我要提交，然后在崩溃之前崩溃
happy it says yes I'm going to commit
and then it crashes before it gets the
现在，我们已经很好地提交了交易雇主协调员的消息
commit message from the transaction
employer coordinator well now we had
如果被告知这样做，我们将处于完全不同的情况
we're in a totally different situation B
is promised to commit if told to do so
因为发送肯定答复，并且所有人都知道，实际上是最有可能发生的事情
because the send a yes back and for all
knows and indeed the most likely thing
发生这种情况的是交易协调员从a和B以及a
that's happening is the transaction
coordinator got yeses from a and B and a
向a发送了一条提交消息，以便a实际上将其部分
sent a commit message to a so that a
actually will do its part of the
交易并使其永久化并释放锁，在这种情况下依次
transaction and make it permanent and
release locks and in that case in order
为了兑现全部或全部，我们绝对需要B在这一点上崩溃
to honor all or nothing we're absolutely
required it B should crash at this point
恢复后仍准备完成其部分
that on recovery that it be still
prepared to complete its part of the
当时还不知道的交易
transaction
it doesn't actually know at that point
您是否知道是因为尚未收到委员会的书，以及是否
whether you know because it hasn't
received the committee ette and whether
它是否应该提交，但仍必须准备提交，以及
it should commit or not but it must
still be prepared to commit and what
这意味着我们不能在整个交易中失去交易状态
that means the fact that we can't lose
the state for a transaction across
崩溃并重新启动是在B回复准备之前
crashes and reboots
is that before B replies to a prepare it
必须使事务状态成为这种中间事务状态
must make the transaction state this
sort of intermediate transaction state
进行的所有更改的内存，如果需要，则必须撤消
the memory of all of the changes that's
made which may have to be undone if
有一个异常中止加上所有锁的记录，记录了交易如何进行
there's an abort plus the record of all
the locks the transactions how it held
它必须使磁盘之间的持久性几乎始终处于登录状态
it must make that durable on disk in
between it's almost always in a log on
磁盘，因此在B答复之前是B会在B发送s4答复准备之前
disk so before B replies yes before B
sends the s4 in reply to a prepare
消息，它首先必须在其日志中写入磁盘所需的所有信息
message it first must write to disk in
its log all the information required to
提交该交易，该交易是put产生的所有新值加上一个完整的
commit that transaction that is all the
new values produced by put plus a full
磁盘或其他持久性存储器上的锁列表，然后应用
list of locks on the disk or some other
persistent memory before applying with
是的，然后是否应该有B是理智后的崩溃，那是
yes and then if there should be if it
B's your crash after sanity yes that's
恢复的一部分，当它重新启动时，请看一下他的日志并说哦，天哪
part of recovery when it restarts that a
look at his it's log and say oh gosh I
在交易中间，我对交易92的回答是“是”
was in the middle of a transaction I had
replied yes for transaction 92 I mean
您知道这是提交后应该进行的所有修改以及所有
you know here's all the modifications it
should make if committed and all the
锁定它，我最好恢复该状态，然后
locks it held
I better restore that state and then
当他最终获得​​承诺或中止时，通过阅读其承诺将会知道
when he finally gets a commitment nor an
abort it'll know from having read its
记录如何实际完成交易的一部分，所以这是一个
log how to actually finish its part of
the transaction so so this is an
我从该协议的原始布局中遗漏的重要一件事是
important thing I left out of the
original laying out of this protocol is
B必须在此时写入其磁盘
that B must write to its disk at this
point
这是使两阶段提交速度稍慢的部分原因在于
and this is part of what makes two-phase
commit a little bit slow is that there's
这些必要的信息持续存在在这里，所以我们也必须
these necessary persisting of
information here okay so we also have to
担心还可以，您知道我可能最后撞到的地方是
worry about okay and you know the final
place I guess where you might crash is
您可能会因为接收到提交或之后两者都崩溃而崩溃
you might crash be my crashed after
receiving the commit or or after both
在实际处理提交之后，您可能会崩溃，但是在那之后
you might crash after actually
processing the commit and but in that
如果进行了修改，则交易意味着永久
case it's made modifications that the
transaction means to make permanent in
它的数据库大概也在收到提交之前在磁盘上
its database presumably also on disk
before after it received a commit
消息，在这种情况下，如果重新启动，则可能无需执行任何操作
message and in that case there's maybe
not anything to do if it restarts
因为事务已完成，所以当B收到提交消息时
because the transaction is finished so
when B receives the commit message it
可能会将修改的副本从其登录写入其
probably writes the copies the
modifications from its log on to its
永久存储释放此锁定会删除有关
permanent storage releases this locks
erases the information about the
几个月的交易记录，然后答复，我们当然要担心
transaction of months log and then
replies and of course we have to worry
关于您知道如果两次收到提交消息可能正确吗
about you know what if it receives a
commit message twice probably the right
要做的是让B记住占用内存的事务
thing to do is either for B to remember
about the transaction that takes memory
因此事实证明，B只是忘记了已提交的事务
so it turns out that it B simply forgets
about committed transactions that it's
使其在磁盘上具有持久性，如果没有，则可以回复重复的提交消息
made durable on disk it can reply to a
repeated commit message if it doesn't
只需再次确认该交易即可了解有关该交易的任何信息，
know anything about that transaction by
simply acknowledging it again and
稍后会很重要，这就是一个故事
that'll be an important a little bit
later on ok so that's the story of one
的参与者在各种尴尬的时刻坠毁，那
of the participants crashes at various
awkward points what about the
交易协调员，也只是一台计算机，对不起，您知道吗
transaction coordinator it's also just a
single computer sorry you know if it
失败可能是个问题，所以再次说明问题开始的关键
fails might be a problem okay so again
the critical where things start getting
关键是如果任何一方可能已经承诺，那么我们就不会忘记
critical is if any party might have
committed then we cannot forget about
如果这些参与者中的任何一个可能已经做出承诺，或者
that if any either of these participants
might have committed or if the
交易协调员可能已经回复了客户，那么我们不能
transaction coordinator might have
replied to the client then we cannot
如果a已提交，则使该交易消失，但是也许它的交易
have that transaction go away right if a
is committed but maybe its transaction
协调员向发出了提交消息，但还没有到
the coordinator sent out a commit
message to a but hadn't gotten around to
发送一个承诺，在那一刻交易崩溃
sending a commitment to be the crashes
at that point the transaction
协调器必须在重新启动时准备好以重新发送提交消息以使
coordinator must be prepared on restart
to resend the commit messages to make
确保双方都知道交易已完成，所以您
sure that both parties know that the
transaction is committed so okay so you
知道这是否重要取决于交易协调员在哪里
know whether that matters depends on
where the transaction coordinator
如果崩溃是在发送提交消息之前崩溃的，那真的没关系
crashes if the crash is before sending
commit messages it doesn't really matter
因为交易协调员未发送，所以您知道双方都不知道
neither party if you know since the
transaction coordinator didn't send
在崩溃之前提交消息，它可以中止事务，如果有的话
commit messages before crashing it can
just abort the transaction and if either
参与者询问该交易，因为他们知道交易发生在他们的
participant asks about that transaction
because they you know see it's in their
日志，但他们从未收到提交消息，事务协调员可以说我
log but they never got a commit message
the transaction coordinator can say I
对该交易一无所知，它必须已中止
don't know anything about that
transaction it must have been aborted
可能是因为当机，如果交易协调员会发生这种情况
possibly due to a crash so that's what
happens if the transaction coordinator
在提交之前崩溃，但是如果在发送一个或多个之后崩溃
crashes before the commit but if a
crashes after sending one or more
提交消息，则它无法捍卫行动协调员，不允许
commits message then it cannot defends
action coordinator can't be allowed to
忘记交易，这意味着什么时候
forget about the transaction and what
that means is that at this point when
在事务协调器之后，它进行了提交或中止操作
that after the transaction coordinator
it's made its commit versus abort
在发出任何提交之前，基于这些是/否表决决定
decision on the basis of these yes/no
votes before sending out any commit
消息，它必须首先将有关交易的信息写入登录
messages it must first write information
about the transaction to its login in
永久性存储，例如磁盘，如果崩溃，它将仍然存在
persistent storage like a disk that will
still be there if it crashes and
重新启动，以便事务协调器在收到完整的是或
restarts so transaction coordinator
after receives a full set of yeses or
noes将结果和事务ID写入磁盘上的日志，然后
noes writes the outcome and the
transaction ID to its log on disk and
只有这样，它才会开始发出提交消息，并且如果崩溃发生在
only then it starts to send out commit
messages and that way if a crash is at
可能在它的第一条提交消息结束之前或发送之后，或者
any point maybe before its end the first
commit message or after its sent one or
也许甚至在发送所有文件后都崩溃了，这表明其恢复软件
maybe even after sent all of them if it
crashes that point its recovery software
将在事务中间的日志AHA中看到该事务
will see in the log AHA which is in the
middle of a transaction the transaction
已知已被提交或中止
was either known to have been committed
or aborted
作为恢复的一部分，它将向所有参与者重新发送提交消息
and as part of recovery it will resend
commit messages to all the participants
或中止任何决定，以防万一之前没有发送过消息
or abort messages whatever the decision
was in case it hadn't sent them before
它崩溃了，这就是为什么参与者必须做好准备的原因之一
it crashed and that's one reason why the
participants have to be prepared to
接收重复的提交消息好吗
receive duplicated commit messages okay
所以还有其他一些是我们也要担心的主要崩溃故事
so there's some other so those are the
main crash stories we also have to worry
关于如果网络中丢失了消息会发生什么，您可能会发送一条消息
about what happens if messages are lost
in the network you might send a message
也许消息从未到达那里，您可能会发送一条消息并等待
maybe the message never got there you
might send a message and be waiting for
回复可能是已发送的回复，但回复已被删除，因此其中任何一个
a reply maybe the reply was sent but the
reply was dropped so any one of these
邮件可能会被丢弃，需要仔细考虑实际操作
messages may be dropped and need to
think through what to actually do in
在每种情况下，例如，假设交易协调员
each of these cases so for example
supposing the transaction coordinator
发送了准备消息，但没有得到某些是或否答复
sent out prepare messages but hasn't
gotten some of the yes or no replies
参与者的交易协调员选项是什么
from participants what are the
transaction coordinators options at that
我可以做的一件事是发出一组新的准备消息，说
point well one thing I could do is send
out a new set of prepare messages saying
你知道我没有得到你的答案，请告诉我你的答案是或否，你
you know I didn't get your answer please
tell me your answer yes or no and you
我知道我可以继续这样做一段时间，但是如果游击队员之一是
know I could keep on doing that for a
while but if one of the partisans is
长时间下来，我们不想坐在那里等着正确的锁
down for a long time we don't want to
sit there waiting with locks held right
因为您知道假设a没有反应，但B处于上升状态，但是因为
because you know supposing a is
unresponsive but but B is up but because
我们尚未提交或中止B仍在持有锁，这可能
that we haven't committed or aborted B
is still holding locks and that may
导致其他交易正在等待，因此如果我们不想永远等待
cause other transactions to be waiting
so we don't want to wait forever if we
可以避免这种情况，如果交易协调员还没有
can possibly avoid it so if the
transaction coordinator hasn't gotten
参与者经过一定时间后回答是或否，则可以
yes or no responses after some amount of
time from the participants then it can
只是单方面决定我们将中止此交易，因为它知道
simply unilaterally decide we're gonna
abort this transaction because it knows
因为它没有得到完整的是或否消息，当然不能
since it didn't get a full set of yes or
no messages of course that can't
可能已经发送了提交，因此没有参与者可以提交，因此
possibly have sent a commit yet so no
participant could have committed so it's
如果事务协调器尚未提交，则始终有效以中止该操作，因此
always valid to abort if the transaction
coordinator hasn't yet committed so the
事务协调器超时，等待是或否x'此消息
transaction coordinator times out
waiting for yes or no x' this messages
迷路或有人坠毁等
were lost or somebody crashed or
something
它可以决定我们是否正在中止我们将发送的交易
it can just decide alright we're
aborting this transaction we'll send out
一轮中止消息，如果有参与者重生并说
a round of abort messages and if some
participant comes back to life and says
哦，您知道我没有收到有关交易95的回音
oh you know I didn't hear back from you
about transaction 95 the transaction
协调员将与您见面哦，我对交易95一无所知
coordinator will see you oh well I don't
know anything about transaction 95
因为它中止了交易并删除了该交易的状态，因此它将
because it aborted it and erased its
State for that transaction and it will
告诉参与者您知道如果
tell the participant you know you should
abort this transaction too similarly if
参与者之一超时在这里等待准备者，然后您
one of the participants times out
waiting for the preparer here then you
知道参与者没有收到准备者，这意味着它没有发送是
know for participant hasn't received a
preparer that means it hasn't send a yes
消息返回，这意味着协调器不可能发送任何消息
message back and that means the
coordinator can't possibly have sent any
提交消息，以便如果参与者在这里鸣叫
commit messages
so if participant chimes out here
等待准备者，也总是可以纾困，
waiting for the preparer it's also
always allowed to just bail out and
决定中止交易，如果是将来某个时候交易
decide to abort the transaction and if
it's some future time the transaction
协调员复活并发出准备消息，然后B会拒绝
coordinator comes back to life and sends
out preparer messages then B will say no
我对那笔交易一无所知，所以我投反对票，那就是
I don't know anything about that
transaction so I'm voting no and that's
好吧，因为它不可能在任何地方开始提交，所以
okay because it can't possibly have
committed started to commit anywhere so
如果网络或交易协调器出现问题，请再次输入
again if something goes wrong with the
network or the transaction coordinator
停了一会儿，参与者仍在等待
is down for a while
and the participants are still waiting
对于准备工作，参与者中止并因此始终有效
for prepares it's always valid for
participants to abort and thereby
释放其他事务可能正在等待的锁，并且
release the locks that other
transactions may be waiting for and that
在繁忙的系统中可能非常重要
can be very important in a busy system
所以这是有关参与者或交易的好消息
so that's the good news about if the
participants or the transaction
协调员超时等待来自其他方的消息
coordinators time out waiting for
messages from the other parties however
假设参与者B已收到准备者并发送了“是”，则
suppose participant B has received a
preparer and sent its yes and so is in
在这里的某个地方，但尚未收到提交，正在等待，
somewhere around here but it hasn't
received a commit and it's waiting and
等待，它还没有提交回来，也许是出问题了
waiting and it hasn't gotten to commit
back maybe something's wrong with the
网络，也许交易协调者是它的网络连接
network maybe the transaction
coordinator is its network connection
已经掉线或电源失效或其他原因，但无论出于何种原因B
has fallen out or its powers failed or
something but for whatever reason B is
等待了很长时间，它现在仍未听到提交，但它一直在坐
waited a long time and it still hasn't
heard a commit now but it's sitting
那里的所有记录仍然保持着这些锁
there holding locks is still holding on
to those locks for all the records that
被使用，这是交易的一部分，这意味着其他
were used and it's part of the
transaction and that means other
事务也可能被阻止，等待这些锁被锁住
transactions may be also
blocked waiting for those locks to be
发布，所以我们很想边界，如果我们可以或发布
released so we're like pretty eager to a
border if we possibly can or release the
锁定，所以问题是B是否已收到准备并回答是
locks and so the question is if B has
received prepare and replied with yes
等待说您知道10后，无权单方面中止
isn't entitle to unilaterally abort
after it's waited say you know 10
秒或10分钟之类的时间来获取提交消息和答案
seconds or 10 minutes or something to
get the commit message and the answer to
不幸的是，在收到我们准备的食物之后，该地区没有
that unfortunately is no in this region
after receiving the prepare we're out
确实是在发送“是”之后并获得提交之前，这是您的超时
really after sending the yes and before
getting the commit it's your time out
等待您不允许中止的提交，您必须继续等待
waiting for the commit you're not
allowed to abort you must keep waiting
您通常必须在协议的此区域调用block，否则
you must usually called block so in this
region of the protocol if you don't
收到您必须无限期等待的提交，原因是
receive the commit you have to wait
indefinitely and the reason is that
因为被发送回是，这意味着交易协调员可能有
since be sent back a yes that means the
transaction coordinator may have
收到是，可能已经收到所有参与者的同意，并且
received the yes it may have received
yes from all of the participants and it
可能已经开始向某些参与者发送提交消息，并且
may have started sending out commit
messages to some of the participants and
这意味着a可能实际上已经看到了提交消息并提交了，
that means that a may have actually seen
the commit message and committed and
使我们的更改永久且未锁定，并显示其他更改
made us changes permanent and unlocked
and showing the changes to other
交易，因为这可能是B的所有B知道的情况
transactions and since that could be the
case for all B knows in this region of
协议B不能单方面决定在必须超时时中止
the protocol B cannot unilaterally
decide to abort at the times out it must
无限期地等待交易协调员的通知，只要它
wait indefinitely to hear from the
transaction coordinator as long as it
需要一些人来修理交易协调员，并且
takes some human may have to come and
repair the transaction coordinator and
终于让它重新开始，并让它读取此日志，看看哦，是的，您
finally get it started again and have it
read this log and see oh yes you
提交了该事务，并最终发送了长时间延迟的提交消息，因此
committed that transaction and finally
send long delayed commit messages so and
同样，如果在某个时候我不能，你不能单方面中止，事实证明
similarly if on a time I you can't you
can't unilaterally abort it turns out
您也不能单方面提交，因为对于所有B来说，a都知道
you can't unilaterally commit either
because for all B knows a might have
投了反对票，但他还没有收到重要信息，因此您可以
voted no but he just hasn't got the
important message yet so you could in
您可以中止或提交该区域
this region you can either abort nor
commit
超时，所以实际上这是一种阻塞行为
on a timeout and so this actually this
this blocking behavior is sort of
两阶段提交的关键属性，不是一个快乐的属性
critical property of two-phase commit
and it's not a happy property
这意味着如果出现问题，您很容易会遇到这种情况
it means if things go wrong you can
easily be in the situation where you
不得不等待很长一段时间才能拥有锁并阻止其他交易
have to wait for a long time with locks
held and holding up other transactions
因此，人们尤其努力地使这一部分成为
and so among other things people try
really hard to make this part of
两阶段提交的行为尽可能快地达到了人类的预期，因此
two-phase commit acts as fast as humanly
possible so that the window of time in
失败可能导致您长时间持有锁而阻塞的原因是
which a failure might cause you to block
with locks held for a long time is as
尽可能小，以便他们尝试使协议的这一部分非常
small as possible so they try to make
this part of the protocol very
轻量级协议，甚至具有某些特定情况下的协议变体
lightweight or even have variants of the
protocols that for certain special cases
可能根本不必等待，所以这是基本协议之一
may not have to wait at all okay so
that's the basic protocol one thing to
请注意，这是我们能够进入
notice about this that is a fundamental
part of why we're able to get to
实际上建立了一个协议，允许a和B都可以对它们都进行排序
actually build a protocol that allows a
and B to sort of both you know they both
提交，或者它们都有或中止的原因之一就是
commit or they both have or abort one
reason for that is that really the
由单个实体做出决定，由交易协调员做出决定
decision is made by a single entity it's
made by the transaction coordinator
除了a和B都不投票，a和B都不是他们
alone a and B are neither of them you
know except that they vote no neither a
B也没有决定是否承诺，他们当然没有参与
nor B is deciding whether to commit or
not and they certainly are not engaged
互相交谈以尝试就什么是
in a conversation with each other to try
to reach agreement about what is the
其他想法，或者他们认为承诺可能都是承诺，相反，我们有
other thinking or they thinking commit
may be all commit to instead we have
这基本上是一种非常简单的协议，其中只有
this much is quite sort of fundamentally
simple protocol in which only the
交易协调员将决策设为单个实体，
transaction coordinator makes the
decision a single entity and it just
告诉对方这是我的决定，请为
tells the other party here's my decision
please go do it the penalty for that for
让交易协调员真正由单个实体完成最终交易
having the transaction coordinator
really the single entity make the final
再次决定的事实是，您必须阻止某些方面
decision again is the fact that you have
to block there's some points in which
您必须阻止等待交易记录协调员
you have to block waiting for the
transaction recording coordinator to
告诉你这个决定是什么，另一个问题是我们知道
tell you what the decision
was one further question is that we know
交易协调员必须记住有关交易的信息
the transaction coordinator must
remember information about transactions
和它的崩溃日志，所以一个问题是何时进行交易
and its log in case it crashes and so
one question is when the transaction
协调员可以忘记其日志中有关交易和
coordinator can forget about information
in its log about transactions and the
答案是，如果它设法从中获得全套确认
answer to that is that if it manages to
get a full set of acknowledgments from
参与者然后知道所有参与者都知道
the participants then it knows that all
the participants know that that
事务已提交或中止，表明所有事务都没有参与者
transaction committed or aborted that
all the transactions no participants
知道那笔交易的命运并尽了自己的本分，并且会
knew the fate of that transaction and
have done their part in it and will
永远都不需要知道信息，因为他们俩都承认了
never need to know that information
right as they both acknowledged it so
当交易协调员得到确认时，它可以擦除所有
when the transaction coordinator gets
acknowledgements it can erase all
信息全部存储在交易中
information all memory the transaction
同样，参与者一旦收到提交或中止消息，并且
similarly participants once they
received a commit or abort message and
完成了交易的一部分，并使更新永久生效，
done their part of the transaction and
made their updates permanent and
那时释放锁，参与者也可以完全忘记
released their locks at that point the
participants also can completely forget
他们将确认函发回给
about that transaction after they send
their acknowledgment back to the
交易协调员现在当然可能无法获得交易协调员
transaction coordinator now of course
the transaction coordinator may not get
他们的确认，并且可以发送，因此可以决定重新发送
their acknowledgement and may send and
may therefore decide to resend the
提交有关理论的消息，也许它丢失了，在这种情况下
commit message on the theory that maybe
it was lost and in that case a
参与者，如果它收到其知道的交易的提交消息
participant if it receives a commit
message for a transaction which it know
没什么，因为它被遗忘了，那么参与者可以
nothing about because it's forgotten
about it then the participant can just
发回另一个确认，因为它知道它得到了提交
send another acknowledgement back
because it knows that it gets a commit
未知事务的消息，一定是因为它已经忘记了
message for an unknown transaction it
must be because it had forgotten about
因为它已经知道它是提交还是中止了，所以
it because it already knew whether it
committed or aborted okay so that's
两阶段提交，用于原子承诺，仅提供一点视角两阶段
two-phase commit for atomic commitment
for a little perspective two-phase
commit在许多已拆分数据的分片数据库中使用
commit is used in a lot of sharded
databases that have split up their data
在多台服务器之间，专门用于数据库或存储
among multiple servers and it's used
specifically in databases or storage
需要支持交易记录的系统
systems that need to support
transactions in which records in which
可以读取或写入多个记录，其中有一个
multiple
records may be read or written there's a
很多更专业的存储系统，这些系统不允许您拥有
lot of some more specialized storage
systems that don't allow you to have
多个记录上的交易，对于它们，您不需要它，您不需要
transactions on multiple records and for
them you don't need it you no need this
如果存储系统不允许，则您不需要两阶段提交
kind of you don't need two-phase commit
if the storage system doesn't allow
多记录交易，但是如果您有多记录交易，并且您
multi record transactions but if you
have multi record transactions and you
将数据分片到多个服务器上，那么您需要支持
shard the data across multiple servers
then you need to support either
牙膏，如果您想获得资产，则需要支持两次提速
toothpaste you need to support two in
pace commit if you want to get asset
事务，但是两阶段提交有一个弊端
transactions
however two-phase commit has an evil
声誉的一个原因是由于多轮消息导致速度很慢，
reputation one reason is it's slow due
to multiple rounds of messages there's a
为了获得涉及多个交易的交易，在这里进行了很多讨论
lot of chitchat here in order to get a
transaction that involves multiple
参与者要完成他们的任务，此外还有许多磁盘写入
participants to finish theirs in
addition a lot of disk writes both a and
B不仅要在准备和发送之间将数据写入其磁盘
B have to not just write data to their
disk between the prepare and the sending
是的，他们必须等待该磁盘速率完成，所以如果
of the yes they have to wait for that
disk rate to finish so certainly if
您使用的机械驱动器需要10毫秒的时间才能附加到
you're using a mechanical Drive that
takes 10 milliseconds to append to the
记录严重限制了参与者的处理速度
log that puts a real serious limit on
how fast participants can process
您知道的10毫秒内的交易会弹出，这意味着没有一些聪明就不会
transactions you know 10 milliseconds a
pop means no without some cleverness
您被限制为每秒100笔交易，这非常慢，而且
you're limited to 100 transactions per
second which is pretty slow and in
此外，交易协调员还必须指出
addition the transaction coordinator
also has a point in which it must after
它收到最后一个是，他们必须首先写入其日志以确保数据为
it receives the last yes they must first
write to its log make sure the data is
安全地放在磁盘上，然后才允许发送该提交消息，并且
safe on disk and only then is that
allowed to send that commit messages and
那又是10毫秒，而这两个都是10毫秒的周期
参与者持有哪些锁，其他事务变慢，并且
which locks are held in the participants
and other transactions are slowed up and
我一直提到，但这非常重要，因为在繁忙的交易中
I keep mentioning that but it's very
important because in a busy transaction
处理系统中有很多交易，其中许多可能是
processing system there's lots and lots
of transactions and many of them may be
等待相同的数据，我们真的更希望不要将锁保持在
waiting for the same data and we'd
really prefer not to hold locks over
很长一段时间内，有很多消息来回传递
long periods of time in which there's
lots of messages going back and forth
那么我们必须等待长时间的耻辱，但是两阶段提交迫使我们去做
这些重量
those weights
另一个问题是，如果发生任何错误，则会丢失消息
and a further problem with it is that if
anything goes wrong messages are lost
某些东西会崩溃，如果不是，那么就崩溃了，那么
参加者必须等待很长时间才能持有锁
participants have to wait for long times
with locks held
因此，面对承诺，您实际上只会在相对较小的范围内看到它
您不在一个组织内的单个机房中的域
domains within a single machine room
within a single organization you don't
例如看到它，您是否在不同银行之间的银行之间进行转账
see it for example did you transfers
between banks between different banks
如果您已在银行中绘制了数据库图表，则可能会看到它，但是您
you might possibly see it within a bank
if it's charted its database but you
永远不会看到两天可以在不同的组织之间运行
would never see two days can it run
between distinct organizations that were
可能由于业务阻塞而在物理上是分开的，您不想
maybe physically separate because of
this blocking business you don't want to
让您的命运知道您的数据库及其在数据库中是否可运行
put the fate of you know your database
and whether it's operational in the
其他组织的手，他们在错误的时间崩溃
hands of some other organization where
they crash at the wrong time you're
强迫您的数据库被迫长时间持有锁，因为
forced your database was forced to hold
locks for a long time and because it's
太慢了，或者做很多研究
so slow also there's a lot a lot of
research has gone into either making it
快速或以各种方式放宽规则，以便更快或
fast or relaxing the rules in various
ways to allow to be faster or
在非常具体的情况下专门针对两阶段提交
specializing two-phase commit for very
specific situations in which you know
您可以剃刮一条消息或将其写入磁盘或其他内容，因为您
you can shave a message or write to the
disk or something off it because you
知道你很好地支持某种有限的交易
know you're only supporting a certain
limited kind of transaction so well
我们将看到相当多的钱，其余的问题是
we'll see fair amount of this and the
rest of the course one question that
在这个交流中，您在这里有了很多领导者，
comes up a lot this exchange here where
you have a leader essentially and it
将这些消息发送给关注者，您知道我们只能继续前进
sends these messages to the followers
and you know we can only go forward if
领导者只有在收到您知道的确认后才能继续进行
the leader can only proceed if it
receives you know acknowledgments
来自足够多的追随者的回复这看起来很像筏
replies from enough of the followers
this looks a lot like raft this
构造看起来很像筏，但是协议的属性
construction looks a lot like raft
however the properties of the protocol
你从中得到的东西与我们得到的东西完全不同
and what you get out of it turn out to
be quite different from what we get out
他们解决了很多不同的问题
of raft they solve very different
problems
因此，思考的方法是使用筏来获得高可用性
so the way to think about it is that you
use raft to get high-availability by
在多个对等方的多个参与者上复制数据，即
replicating data on multiple
participants on multiple peers that is
筏子的目的是即使一些服务器的
the point of raft is to be able to
operate even though some of the server's
涉及的崩溃或无法到达，您可以在木筏上进行此操作
involved have crashed or are not
reachable and you can do this in raft
筏可以做到这一点，因为所有服务都在做他们正在做的相同的事情
raft can do this because all the service
are doing the same thing they're doing
同样的事情，所以我们不需要所有人参与，我们只需要一个
the same thing so we don't need all of
them to participate we only need a
多数两阶段提交，但是参与者根本没有做
majority two-phase commit however the
participants are not at all doing the
参与者各自都在做不同的事情
same thing the participants are each
doing a different part of the
您知道的交易可能会增加记录X和B
transaction you know a maybe
incrementing record X and B maybe
递减记录Y因此两阶段提交所有培训所有参与者
decrementing record Y so two-phase
commit all the train all the participant
他们都必须尽自己的一份努力才能使交易真正完成
they all have to do their part in order
for the transaction to finish you really
需要等待每一个参与者做他们的事情，好吗
need to wait for every single one of the
participants to do their thing so okay
这样我们就知道筏是复制品，不需要每个人都做
so we got you know raft is replicating
doesn't need everybody to do their thing
两阶段提交每个人都在做不同的事情
two-phase commit
everybody's doing something different
必须完成两阶段提交的操作对可用性完全没有帮助
that has to get done two-phase commit
does not help at all with availability
你知道筏子是关于可用性的，即使一些
you know raft is all about availability
you can go on even if some of the
参与者没有响应实际上根本没有两阶段提交
participants are not responding
two-phase commit is actually not at all
如果有任何问题，它根本就不是高度可用，我们冒风险
available it's not highly available at
all if anything goes wrong we risk
如果事务协调器在崩溃时必须等待修复
having to wait until that's repaired if
the transaction coordinator crashes at
错误的时间，我们只需要等待上来并阅读其日志并发送
the wrong time we simply have to wait
for to come up and read its log and send
如果您认识的这些参与者之一崩溃了，就发出提交消息吧
out the commit messages right if if one
of these participants you know crashes
在错误的时间，您知道我们是否很幸运，我们只需要中止然后我们
at the wrong time you know if we're
lucky we simply have to abort then we're
不走运，我们不得不说你完成了吗，你完成了那么两阶段
not lucky we have to say did you finish
that did you finish that so two-phase
提交根本不是关于高可用性的，实际上是
commit is not at all about high
availability in fact it's it's a it's
这样的可用性很低，任何崩溃都可能占用整个系统
quite low availability as such things go
any crash can hold up the whole system
当然，木筏并不能确保所有参与者都能做到
and of course raft doesn't ensure that
all the participants do whatever the
操作只需要多数就可以了
operation is it only requires a majority
there may be
完全根本不做手术的少数人，这就是事实
minority that totally didn't do the
operation at all and that's how the fact
筏所有参与者都做同样的事情，我们不必等待所有
that raft all the participants do the
same thing we don't have to wait for all
其中一个就是为什么筏具有高可用性，所以这些
of them is why raft gets high
availability so these are quite
不同的协议，但是可以将它们有效地组合在一起
different protocols um it is however
possible to to usefully combine them
就像两阶段提交一样，您知道确实很容易遭受失败，这是正确的
like two-phase commit is you know really
vulnerable to failures it's correct with
失败，但其他人无法使用，所以问题是
failures but it's not available with the
others so the question is could you
建立某种组合的系统，该系统具有RAF的高可用性
build some sort of combined system that
has the high availability of RAF to
复制，但具有两个阶段提交功能，可以调用各种不同的
replication but has two phase commits
ability to call as various different
各方各自负责交易和建设
parties each to do their part of the
transaction and the construction you
实际上想要使用的是筏或paxos或类似的其他协议来表示
want actually is to use raft or paxos or
some other protocol like that to rep
分别复制每个不同的参与者，因此我们将
individually replicate each of the
different parties so then we would for
这样设置，我们将需要三个不同的集群进行交易
this set up we would have like three
different clusters the transaction
您知道三台服务器，并且实际上协调器将被复制服务
coordinator would actually be replicated
service with you know three servers and
你知道我们将在这三台服务器上运行木筏，其中一台将当选为领导
you know we'd run raft on these three
servers one will be elected as leader
他们会复制状态，他们有一个日志可以帮助他们复制我们
they'd have replicated state they'd have
a log that helped them replicate we
不仅需要等待大多数人的领导，我们只需要拥有一个
don't only have to wait for a majority
the leader we'd only have to have a
为了使交易协调员能够做到
minority of these to be up in order for
the transaction coordinator to do its
工作，当然他们都会，而且您知道通过
work and of course they would all and
you know sort of execute through the
交易的各个阶段以及两阶段提交协议
various stages of the transaction and
the two-phase commit protocol by
基本上是将相关记录附加到他们的日志中，然后每个
basically by appending relevant records
to their logs and then each of the
参与者也将是我们筏复制集群的代表集群
participants would also be a cluster of
a rep our raft replicated cluster
所以我们最终会和他们来回交换信息链
so we would end up and they would chain
exchange messages back and forth you
知道我们会从复制的事务协调器发送提交消息
know we'd send a commit message from the
replicated transaction coordinator
服务到复制的服务器和复制的B服务器，这就是您
service to the replicated a server and
the replicated B server and this is you
知道这固然有些复杂，但确实显示出您
know this is admittedly somewhat
elaborate but it does show you that you
可以将这些想法结合起来以获得高可用性，因为
can combine these ideas to get the
combination of high availability because
这些服务器中的任何一台都可能崩溃，而其余两台则继续运行
any one of these servers can crash and
the remaining two you keep operating
再加上我们对a和B的原子承诺正在完全不同
plus we get on this atomic commitment of
a and B are doing complete different
同一笔交易的一部分，我们可以使用两阶段提交
parts of the same transaction and we can
use two-phase commit to have the
交易协调员确保您都知道两者都承担了全部责任
transaction coordinator ensure that you
know that either both commit the whole
事情，或者它们都中止了您将实际构建的事务的一部分
thing or they both abort their parts of
the transaction you'll actually build
作为实验室表格的一部分，它非常像这样，您确实会建立一个
something very much like this as part of
lab form which you will indeed build a
分片数据库，其中每个分片都以这种形式复制，并且有一个
shard a database where each shard is
replicated in this form and there's a
基本上是一个配置管理器，它将基本上允许事务性
basically a configuration manager which
will allow essentially transactional
将数据碎片从一个筏群集转移到另一个筏群集
shifting of chunks of shards of data
from one raft cluster to another under
看起来很像交易协调员的东西的控制，所以
the control of something that looks a
lot like a transaction coordinator so
实验4就是这样，此外，我们还将阅读一篇论文
lab 4 is like this and in addition in a
little bit we'll be reading a paper
称为扳手，它描述了Google使用的真实数据库
called spanner which describes a
real-life database used by Google that
用户还使用此构造来对
users also uses this construction in
order to do transactional writes to a
数据库好了谢谢
database all right thank you